RYAN HUBBUCK

Software Developer

OBJECTIVE

As a self-taught software developer who has a background of three years of freelance website development and one year working with Tombras Group, I am seeking a position in a growth-oriented company where I can use my skills to the advantage of the organization while having the scope and direction to develop my own skills as a programmer.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Tombras Group - Associate Software Engineer 2022–Present

- Maintain and build websites and applications for corporate and government entities utilizing languages such as C++, PHP, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS
- Build custom components with ReactJS and PHP
- Manage code repositories with Git and Jira
- Work closely with the design team using Figma and QA to ensure performance optimization and client vision fulfillment, while participating in code reviews, code testing, and incorporating documentation
- Build custom components utilizing ReactJS and PHP
- Troubleshoot and debug code in a time-efficient manor to address issues as they arise anywhere within my team

Self-employed - Freelance Web Developer 2020–Present

- Develop personal landing pages, e-commerce sites, and smallbusiness pages for clients using various back-end tools such as Firebase and/or WordPress CMS.
- Complete full website design process with input from client to ensure their vision is executed
- Provide SEO optimization and subscription/ communication for subscribers and clients
- Educate client on basic functionality and provide ongoing support/ education for future changes

EDUCATION

Southern New Hampshire University – 2022-2024 exp. B.S. Computer Science 4.0 GPA

Roane State Community College – 2015-2017

Assoc. of Science - Physical Therapist Assistant

Assoc. of Science - Physical Therapist Assistant Summa Cum Laude – 4.0 GPA

SKILLS

JavaScript HTML/CSS React PHP SQL Python C++ Git Docker

Typescript

Linux

CONTACT

PHONE: 865-804-0597

ADDRESS: 2000 Panoramic Way Knoxville, TN 37932

WFBSITE:

https://ryanhubbuck.com

GITHUB:

https://www.github.com/rhubbuck

EMAIL:

rhubbuck@gmail.com

LINKEDIN:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryanhubbuck/